Guide to the School of Nursing, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Nursing, Yale University, records
1918-2012
RU 205
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
572.75
906 boxes
1.57
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, and subject and administrative files documenting the activities of various deans and administrative personnel of the Yale School of Nursing. Topics include finance, faculty, admissions, committees, policy and curriculum, research and public service, national and international associations, visitors, and affiliated universities and hospitals. Included are the records of deans Annie Warburton Goodrich, Effie Taylor, Elizabeth Torrey, Margaret G. Arnstein, and Donna Diers.
Yale University. School of Nursing
Arnstein, Margaret G.
Diers, Donna
Goodrich, Annie Warburton, 1866-
Taylor, Effie J. (Effie Jane), 1874-
Torrey, Elizabeth Bixler, 1901-1976
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 29-A (YRG 29-A), Central records and records of the dean of the Yale School of Nursing.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale School of Nursing began in 1923 under the direction of its first Dean, Annie W. Goodrich. In 1934 the School adopted the policy of admitting only college graduates and, in 1952, the Yale Corporation voted to establish an official graduate program. The basic program was altered in 1956 when it was expanded to prepare nurses in public health, maternal-newborn nursing, and psychiatric nursing. A Master of Science was awarded after a minimum of one year's study and field experience. In 1959-1960 a two-year master's degree was created, and the curriculum was furthered expanded in 1969 to include pediatric nursing and a medical surgery major. In April 1970 the Corporation approved development of a three-year curriculum for college graduates from other fields. The School strives for wide theoretical and practical training, and emphasizes the development of basic skills as well as the importance of specialized training.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, and subject and administrative files documenting the activities of various deans and administrative personnel of the Yale School of Nursing. Topics include finance, faculty, admissions, committees, policy and curriculum, research and public service, national and international associations, visitors, and affiliated universities and hospitals. Included are the records of deans Annie Warburton Goodrich, Effie Taylor, Elizabeth Torrey, Margaret G. Arnstein, and Donna Diers.
Hospitals -- Employees; Hospitals -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Midwifery -- Study and teaching; Nursing schools; Nursing students; Nursing -- Study and teaching; Public health -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Nurses; Connecticut State Nurses' Association; New Haven Hospital (New Haven, Conn.); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Nursing; Yale-New Haven Hospital
- Records, circa 1921-1979; Accession 19ND-A-410
  - Series I
    - Correspondence
      - Hospitals and universities Miscellaneous materials used, 1923-51 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Miscellaneous, 1923-51 (Box 1, Folder 2-11)
        - Hartford College, West Hartford, 1923-51 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - Mt. Holyoke College, South Hadley, Mass., 1923-51 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - Pennsylvania College for Women: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - Pennsylvania State College: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - Pennsylvania University of, publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 16)
        - Pittsburgh, University of: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 17)
        - Publicity: Virginia Kirk, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 18)
        - Radcliffe College, Cambridge, Mass.: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 19)
        - Rockford College, Rockford, Illinois, Rosary College, River Forest, Illinois: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 20)
        - St. Lawrence University, Canton, Mass.: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 21)
        - Simmons College, Boston, Mass., Skidmore College, Saratoga Springs, N.Y.: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 22)
        - Skidmore College, Saratoga Springs, N.Y.: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 23)
        - Smith College, North Hampton, Mass.: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 24)
        - Swarthmore College, Swarthmore, Pa.: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        - Syracuse University, Syracuse, N.Y., Transylvania College, Lexington, Ky.: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 26)
        - Tufts College, Medford, Mass.: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        - Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, N.Y., Vermont, University of, Burlington, Vt. publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - Wellesley College, Wellesley, Mass.: Community Health Association: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - Wells College, Aurora, N.Y.: publicity, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 30)
        - Alumnae Association data: M.D. Taylor, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        - Danbury Hospital, Danbury, Ct., 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 32)
        - Greenwich Hospital Association Butler Hospital, Providence, R.I., 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - Homeopathic Hospital of Rhode Island, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 34)
        - Lawrence and Memorial Hospitals, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 35)
        - Middlesex Hospital, 1924-30 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - New Britain Hospital, 1925-31 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - Norwalk Hospital, Norwalk, Ct. old correspondence, 1923-51 (Box 2, Folder 37)
        - Trudeau Sanatorium, Trudeau, N.Y., -1928 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Dispensary
      - New Haven Hospital General Data, 1924-35 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Report of Supervisor (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Clinic Reports (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Genito Urinary Clinic (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Medical Clinic (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Surgical Orthopedic Clinic (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Pediatric (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Reports of Clinics and Conferences (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - Metabolism (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - Reports of Clinics and Conferences Syphillic Clinic (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - Tuberculosis Clinic (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Woman's Clinic (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Report of Conferences, 1927-29 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Student Nurses' Time, Monthly Reports, 1924-35 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Supervisors Report of Nursing Service, 1926-38 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Reports of Conferences and Clinics Dental Clinic, 1934-42 (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Eye, Ear, Nose and Throat Clinic, 1920-42 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Faculty, General, 1926-32 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Faculty, Departmental Committee (early), 1925-31 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Faculty, Departmental Committee, miscellaneous and early Committee, 1936-50 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Program Committee, 1930-32 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Committee on Institutional Adjustments, 1924-32 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Faculty Council, 1926-29 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Faculty Council, 1930-35 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Agenda for Administration Committee, 1926-37 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Administrative Committee, 1926-1933 (Box 6, Folder 64-69)
    - Administrative Committee, 1934-35 (Box 7, Folder 70-71)
    - Army Nurse Corps (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Army School of Nursing (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Library Committee Minutes, Y.S.N., 1941-55 (Box 7, Folder 74-75)
    - Library Committee, 1924-40 (Box 7, Folder 76-77)
    - Hartford Retreat correspondence, 1932-45 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Hartford Retreat minutes, printed materials, etc., 1936-45 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Hartford Retreat Post-graduate Courses offered, 1937-43 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Committee on Instruction in the Biological and Social Sciences, 1935-42 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1935-45 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Industrial Nursing Project, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Inventory, 1924-49 (Box 8, Folder 84-85)
    - Pediatrics -General -Correspondence, 1925-54 (Box 9, Folder 86)
    - Pediatric Committee, 1924-36 (Box 9, Folder 87)
    - Public Health, Department of, 1926-59 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - Correspondence with Universities and Colleges A-Z, Miscellaneous, 1929-58 (See also Box 1) (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence with Universities and Colleges (Box 9, Folder 90)
      - Individual folders, alphabetically arranged (Box 9, Folder 91-93)
      - Individual folders, alphabetically arranged (Box 10, Folder 94-117)
    - Letters regarding student employment (Box 10, Folder 118)
    - Teachers College 40th Anniversary (Box 10, Folder 119)
    - Advisory Committee, Division of Nursing, University of Rhode Island (Box 10, Folder 120)
    - Connecticut State Nurses' Association, 1952-53 (Box 10, Folder 121)
      - President, 1953-54 (Box 11, Folder 122)
      - Board of Directors, 1951-52 (Box 11, Folder 123)
    - Connecticut State Student Nurses Association (Box 11, Folder 124)
    - Connecticut State Nurses' Association Committee on Defense and Planning (Box 11, Folder 125)
    - Connecticut, miscellaneous, 1951-59 (Box 11, Folder 126)
    - Connecticut, State of - Personnel Department, 1944-54 (Box 11, Folder 127)
    - Connecticut Training School (Box 11, Folder 128)
      - Alumnae and miscellaneous, 1930-58 (Box 11, Folder 128)
      - Board (Box 11, Folder 129)
      - Historical material (Box 11, Folder 130)
    - Connecticut Tuberculosis Association, 1948-54 (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Cottage-Playridge (Henry Wright), 1935-50 (Box 12, Folder 132)
    - Darling, Dr. G. B., Director of Medical Affairs, 1946-52 (Box 12, Folder 133)
    - Board of Administrative Officers, 1935-59 (Box 12, Folder 134)
    - Disaster Nursing, 1957? (Box 12, Folder 135)
    - 136 Dock, Lavinia, 1929-44 (Box 12, Folder 136)
    - 137 District of Columbia, Department of Health, Education & Welfare, 1955-58 (Box 12, Folder 137)
      - Miscellaneous organizations [folder missing], 1948-57 (Box 12, Folder 138)
    - Bursar, 1926-31 (Box 12, Folder 139)
    - Bursar, 1932-37 (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - Bursar, 1938-43 (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - Bursar, 1944-49 (Box 13, Folder 142)
    - Bursar, 1949-53 (Box 13, Folder 143)
    - Bursar, 2 envelopes, bills re: Basic Students, 1947-53 (Box 13, Folder 144)
    - Bills re: Basic Students, 1953-58 (Box 13, Folder 145)
    - Registrars Report, 1924-53 (Box 13, Folder 146)
    - Entertainment, 1928-50 (Box 14, Folder 147)
    - Committee on Admissions, 1934-55 (Box 14, Folder 148)
    - Faculty Council
      - Agendas, 1944-54 (Box 14, Folder 149)
      - Minutes, 1954-57 (Box 14, Folder 150)
      - Minutes, 1950-53 (Box 14, Folder 151)
    - Board of Administrative Officers
      - Minutes of Board Meeting briefed for the President, 1944-52 (Box 14, Folder 152)
      - 1949-53 (Box 15, Folder 153)
      - 1946-48 (Box 15, Folder 154)
      - 1940-45 (Box 15, Folder 155)
      - Executive Committee, 1942-45 (Box 15, Folder 156)
    - Committee on Clinical Instruction
      - 1947-54 (Box 15, Folder 157)
      - 1935-47 (Box 15, Folder 158)
    - Yale School of Nursing -General, 1926-57 (Box 16, Folder 159)
    - Committee on Admissions (Box 16, Folder 160)
    - Committee on Basic Curriculum -minutes, 1948-57 (Box 16, Folder 161)
    - Clinical Coordinating Committee -minutes, 1951-57 (Box 16, Folder 162)
    - Faculty Policies Committee, 1948-49 (Box 16, Folder 163)
    - Sub-committee on Grading, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 164)
    - Surgical Nursing, Committee, 1927-42 (Box 16, Folder 165)
    - Miscellaneous Committees, 1932-59 (Box 16, Folder 166)
    - Nursing Arts Committee, 1936-50 (Box 16, Folder 167)
    - Out-patient Experience Committee, 1950-52 (Box 16, Folder 168)
    - Records Committee, 1945-54 (Box 16, Folder 169)
    - Committee on School and Hospital Relations (formerly Faculty Council), 1935-43 (Box 16, Folder 170)
      - Annual Reports, 1927-35 (Box 16, Folder 171)
    - Forms -Samples of printed, 1936-56 (Box 17, Folder 172)
    - Senior Seminar Committee, 1945-50 (Box 17, Folder 173)
    - University of Connecticut Conference, 1948-52 (Box 17, Folder 174)
    - Foreign Missions, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 175)
    - G -miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 176)
    - Committee on Interpretation (Public Relations), 1951-56 (Box 17, Folder 177)
    - Graduate Courses -Y.S.N.
      - Correspondence with Graduate School re: courses in nursing, 1925-47 (Box 17, Folder 178)
      - Yale Graduate School-not courses in Nursing (Box 17, Folder 179)
      - Other than Yale School of Nursing or Yale Graduate School (Box 17, Folder 180)
    - Booklets
      - Results of the First Grading Study of Nursing Schools, 1930 (3 vols) (Box 17, Folder 181)
      - The Second Grading of Nursing Schools, 1932 (1 copy) (Box 17, Folder 182)
    - Harmon Foundation, 1926-32 (Box 17, Folder 183)
    - Department of Health, Yale University, 1923-58 (Box 18, Folder 184)
    - Report of Number of Students in Residence at Medical Center or in New Haven, 1955-58 (Box 18, Folder 185)
    - Student Nurse Health Service, 1927-58 (Box 18, Folder 186)
    - I - miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 187)
    - Illinois - Miscellaneous Organizations, 1926-46 (Box 18, Folder 188)
    - Indiana - Miscellaneous Organizations, 1936-57 (Box 18, Folder 189)
    - Industrial Nursing, 1949-56 (Box 18, Folder 190)
    - Institute of Living, 1946-57 (Box 18, Folder 191)
    - Institute of Living, 1951-57 (Box 18, Folder 192)
    - Insurance (Box 18, Folder 193)
    - Inventory, 1950-59 (Box 19, Folder 194)
    - Japanese students, problems relating to, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 195)
    - K - miscellaneous correspondence (Box 19, Folder 196)
    - Kentucky - Frontier Nursing Service (Box 19, Folder 197)
    - Lambert Brothers - jewelers (Box 19, Folder 198)
    - Legislation, 194-50, re: nursing (Box 19, Folder 199)
    - Legislation, early material, 1933-43 (Box 19, Folder 200)
    - Librarian, 1934-58 (Box 19, Folder 201)
    - Yale Medical Library Connnittee-Minutes, 1950-59 (Box 19, Folder 202)
    - Library, School of Nursing Accession Lists, 1928-47 (Box 19, Folder 203)
    - Lists - Colleges attended by Y.S.N. Graduates, Set 2 (incomplete). 1 set in Inactive File, Y.S.N. (Box 20, Folder 204)
    - M- Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 205)
    - Microbiology, 1923-53 (Box 20, Folder 206)
    - Dr. Catherine Miles, 1936-44 (Box 20, Folder 207)
    - Nathan Smith Hall -miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 208)
    - Nathan Smith Hall -personnel, 1940-53 (Box 20, Folder 209)
    - National Security Resources Board, 1948-50 (Box 20, Folder 210)
    - Navy Nurse Corps, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 211)
    - Negro-Nurse, Oct, 1936-46 (Box 20, Folder 212)
    - Neurosurgery -miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 213)
    - Nursing Aides -G-NHCH (Box 20, Folder 214)
    - Grace Nursing School Committee
      - 1953-58 (Box 20, Folder 215)
      - 1950-53 (Box 20, Folder 216)
      - 1945-50 (Box 20, Folder 217)
    - Grace-New Haven -Department Heads Meeting, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 218)
    - Medical Board -New Haven Unit, 1949-53 (Box 21, Folder 219)
    - Medical Board -New Haven Unit, 1945-49 (Box 21, Folder 220)
    - New Haven Hospital -Board of Directors, 1935-43 (Box 21, Folder 221)
    - New Haven Hospital -miscellaneous, 1926-46 (Box 21, Folder 222)
    - Reports of Graduate Nurse Employment, 1954-55 (Box 21, Folder 223)
    - G-NHCH Nursing Council Meeting, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 224)
    - Statistics, 1926-45 (Box 21, Folder 225)
    - Annual Reports -Department of Nursing, G-NHCH, 1947-55 (Box 21, Folder 226)
    - Reports of Department of Nursing, G-NHCH, 1924-47 (Box 22, Folder 227)
    - School and Hospital Problems, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 228)
    - New Haven Hospital -Defense Program, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 229)
    - New Haven Hospital -Directors Mr. Buck, Mr. Hamilton, 1933-45 (Box 22, Folder 230)
    - New Haven
      - Miscellaneous Organizations, 1931-48 (Box 22, Folder 231)
      - Children's Community Center (Orphan Asylum), 1930-34 (Box 22, Folder 232)
      - Council of Social Agencies Health Division, Executive Committee, 1945-51 (Box 22, Folder 233)
      - Department of .Health, 1929-33 (Box 22, Folder 234)
      - Council of Social Agencies Prenatal Medical Advisory Committee, 1933-43 (Box 22, Folder 235)
      - Nursing Council of Reports of Secretary, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 236)
      - Council of Social Agencies-Health Division Committee on Nutrition, 1946-1950 (Box 22, Folder 237)
      - Council of Social Agencies Committee on Mental Hygiene, 1945-54 (Box 23, Folder 238)
      - Joint Council: Committee on Nursing Steering Committee (Box 23, Folder 239)
      - Joint Council: Committee on Nursing, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 240)
      - Council of Social Agencies, 1950-51 (Box 23, Folder 241)
      - Mental Hygiene Society, 1943-52 (Box 23, Folder 242)
      - Local Nursing Council for War Service, 1944-48 (Box 23, Folder 243)
      - Nursing Service Bureau, 1927-51 (Box 23, Folder 244)
      - Social Worker Club, 1927-39 (Box 23, Folder 245)
    - Committee on Nurse Recruitment, 1951-52 (Box 23, Folder 246)
    - New Haven Tuberculosis and Health Association, 1946-53 (Box 23, Folder 247)
    - Visiting Nurse Association Board of Directors, 1952-54 (Box 23, Folder 248)
    - Visiting Nurse Association Board of Directors, 1955-58 (Box 23, Folder 249)
    - New Jersey Miscellaneous organizations, 1927-55 (Box 23, Folder 250)
    - New York
      - Miscellaneous organizations, 1930-54 (Box 23, Folder 251)
      - Community Service Society (formerly A.I.C.P.), 1937-49 (Box 23, Folder 252)
      - League of Nursing Education, 1925-51 (Box 24, Folder 253)
      - State Department of Health, 1928-51 (Box 24, Folder 254)
      - State Education Department, 1926-47 (Box 24, Folder 255)
      - State Education Department of Mental Hygiene, 1949-50 (Box 24, Folder 256)
      - State Nurses Association, 1925-50 (Box 24, Folder 257)
    - Notices -Affiliating Students, 1944-53 (Box 24, Folder 258)
    - Notices -Yale Students, 1928-57 (Box 24, Folder 259)
    - Nutrition -miscellaneous, 1927-54 (Box 24, Folder 261)
    - Occupational Therapy, 1932-50 (Box 24, Folder 262)
    - O -miscellaneous, 1926-43 (Box 24, Folder 263)
    - Operating Room, 1936-54 (Box 24, Folder 264)
      - Techniques and Supervision -Post Graduate Course, 1941-51 (Box 24, Folder 265)
        - Outlines, etc., 1945-50 (Box 24, Folder 266)
    - Orthopedics, 1939-3 (Box 25, Folder 267)
    - Pennsylvania -Miscellaneous organizations, 1926-56 (Box 25, Folder 268)
    - Pharmacology, 1928-55 (Box 25, Folder 269)
    - Physiology Department, 1926-53 (Box 25, Folder 270)
    - Physiotherapy, 1929-56 (Box 25, Folder 271)
    - President's Office - G. Seymour, 1937-50 (Box 25, Folder 272)
    - Provost, 1923-53 (Box 25, Folder 273)
    - Psychiatry, 1939-55 (Box 25, Folder 274)
    - Group for the Advancement of Psychiatry, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 275)
    - Psychology - miscellaneous correspondence, 1926-47 (Box 25, Folder 276)
    - Psychological Tests, 1941-52 (Box 25, Folder 277)
    - Psychological Study, 1928-31 (Box 26, Folder 278)
    - Psychology Tests, Affiliating Students, 1924-45 (Box 26, Folder 279-280)
    - Porter Sargent Company, 1926-29 (Box 26, Folder 281)
    - Anderson Classification Tests for Affiliating Students, 1926-41 (Box 26, Folder 282)
    - Miscellaneous Publicity Material, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 283)
    - Public Health Nursing - miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 284)
    - Public Health Hospital Administration Class, 1947-58 (Box 26, Folder 285)
    - Publicity
      - Folder, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 286)
      - Committee on Careers Material Publicity correspondence, 1952-57 (Box 26, Folder 287)
      - Rheta Clueck's correspondence (Box 26, Folder 288)
      - Open House, October 15, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 289)
      - Open House, October 16, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 290)
      - Miscellaneous advertising, 1945-56 (Box 26, Folder 291)
      - Porter-Sargent, 1945-48 (Box 27, Folder 292)
      - Porter-Sargent, 1938-44 (Box 27, Folder 293)
      - Porter-Sargent, 1933-37 (Box 27, Folder 294)
      - Recruitment Correspondence College visits, 1954-56 (Box 27, Folder 295)
      - Old Folders (Box 27, Folder 296)
      - Publicity Committee Reports, 1931-35 (Box 27, Folder 297)
      - Visits to Colleges and Correspondence by Y.S.N. representatives, 1933-38 (Box 27, Folder 298)
      - Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 299)
    - Regulations re: Basic Y.S.N. Program (Box 27, Folder 300)
    - Rehabilitation Program, 1952-53 (Box 27, Folder 301)
    - Frederick W. Roberts, M.D., 1952 (Box 27, Folder 302)
    - Registration Lists of Students (Box 28, Folder 310)
    - S -miscellaneous (Box 28, Folder 311)
    - Schedules -Yale, 1926-30 (Box 28, Folder 312)
    - Leopold Schepp Foundation, 1927-1940 (Box 28, Folder 313)
    - Schedules, Yale, 1931-42 (Box 29, Folder 314)
    - Y.S.N. Department of Obstetrics -Reports, 1954-56 (Box 29, Folder 315)
    - Obstetrics
      - Rooming In Project -correspondence, 1948-51 [Missing] (Box 29, Folder 316)
      - Rooming In Codes, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 317)
      - Outdoor Service, 1928-31 (Box 29, Folder 318)
    - Maternity Institute
      - Applications, Aug. 7-11, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 319)
      - General correspondence, Aug. 7-11, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 320)
      - Nov 28-Dec 2, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 321)
    - Scholarships
      - Institute of International Education, 1944-45 (Box 30, Folder 322)
      - American Legion, 1943-51 (Box 30, Folder 323)
      - American Committee for Nursing Scholarships, 1942-49 (Box 30, Folder 324)
      - Alpha-Phi Sorority Scholarships, 1942-45 (Box 30, Folder 325)
      - Scholarship Loan Fund, 1924-35 (Box 30, Folder 326)
      - Scholarship Loan Fund, 1936-47 (Box 30, Folder 327)
      - Social Service Dept., 1933-51 (Box 30, Folder 328)
    - Sociology, Dept. of, 1937-57 (Box 30, Folder 329)
    - Housing
      - Sterling Dorm, 1941-49 (Box 30, Folder 330)
      - Sterling Dorm, 1951-55 (Box 30, Folder 331)
      - New Dormitory, 1951-55 (Box 30, Folder 332)
      - New Dormitory, 1954-56 (Box 30, Folder 333)
      - Sterling Dorm, 1924-59 (Box 30, Folder 334)
      - Sterling Dorm House Council, 1937-56 (Box 31, Folder 335)
    - Surgery, Dept. of-miscellaneous, 1923-54 (Box 31, Folder 336)
    - Time Studies-graphs, 1935-37 (Box 31, Folder 337)
    - Time Studies (Miss Tracy-Miss Pfefferkorn) Bulletin No. 1, 1928 (Box 31, Folder 338)
    - Treasurer's Office
      - Estimated Budgets, 1946-56 (Box 31, Folder 341)
      - re: Maintenance Transfers, 1942-56 (Box 31, Folder 342)
    - Tuberculosis Clinic, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 343)
    - Tuberculosis Nursing, 1940-54 (Box 31, Folder 344)
    - Uniforms -miscellaneous information, 1927-56 (Box 31, Folder 345)
    - Mid-century White House Conference on Children
      - 1950-51 (Box 32, Folder 346)
      - 1949-50 (Box 32, Folder 347)
      - 1930-31 (Box 32, Folder 348)
    - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), 1944-46 (Box 32, Folder 349)
    - United States Public Health Service (USPHS) Children's Bureau, 1927-1959 (Box 32, Folder 350)
    - Veterans Administration Hospital, West Haven, CT
      - 1953 (Box 32, Folder 351)
      - 1950 (Box 32, Folder 352)
      - Washington, D.C., 1946-51 (Box 32, Folder 353)
      - Requirements for T.B. -Neuropsychiatric, 1946-47 (Box 32, Folder 354)
      - Building (4 booklets) (Box 32, Folder 355)
      - Advisory Committee (Box 32, Folder 356)
    - Virginia: Miscellaneous Organizations, 1924-26 (Box 33, Folder 357)